okay so let's look at one more example
here where I have a series and my series
is like really just kind of complicated
if I try to write out for example what
SN was it would just like be this
horrible mess and we don't really know
how to do anything with it
indeed this pretty much often the case
in the telescoping series we could write
out the SN and everything canceled it
was really neat but in the vast majority
of cases if we try to write out what SN
was it's just gonna be this horrifying
mess so how do we deal with this and if
I look at this I'm like very tempted to
do an integration because I see an e to
the minus N squared and then multiplied
by a power of n on the on the bottom it
kind of like screams you subs to me but
that's something we did back in
integration so let's just compare this
to the improper interval indeed if I
consider the improper integral 1 to
infinity of 4 times X e to the minus x
squared so I'm replacing my n with X
here DX
well I'd first know that this is the
same thing as the limit as T goes to
infinity of the integral from 1 up to T
of 4 X e to the minus x squared DX
that's how I deal with improper under
both I write this as the sort of this
limit of these quote-unquote partial
integrals are sort of analogous to
partial sums in series so if I do a
little bit of the u sub maybe I'm going
to say that U is equal to x squared that
means that D U is equal to 2x DX
if X is equal to 1 that implies that U
is equal to 1 and if X is equal to T
that implies that U is equal to T
squared so I can replace this entire
thing this is just the limit as T goes
to infinity of the integral from 1 up to
T squared I have a 4x so this is a 2 do
you E - the - you do u and this is just
the limit as T goes to infinity of a
minus sign because the e to the minus u
T e to the minus u evaluated between 1
and T squared which is this
same thing as limit as T goes to
infinity of minus 2 e to the minus T
squared all subtracted because I've got
two minus signs I go put a plus sign all
plus 2 e to the minus 1 and then if I
evaluate this as T goes to infinity this
this whole first term is going to zero
so just left with this 2 over e and
therefore that's my answer so that's my
answer for the integral the integral
converges to 2 over e and therefore my
original series from 1 to infinity of 4
and E the minus N squared converges and
again note that I'm not saying it
converges to 2 over e it almost
certainly doesn't I'm merely saying that
it converges